

SUMMARY

Master of Business & Science, a dedicated **Data Specialist** with 3 years' experience including **Digital Platform, Data Cleansing** and **Data Visualization** in Social Media, Health & Medical Device Market. Apart from possessing exceptional **analytical** & **problem-solving** skills, Robin is a great **team player** with excellent **communication** & presentation skills.

- ✓ Digital Platform Automation
- ✓ Data API Orchestration & Troubleshooting
- ✓ Data Cleansing using SQL & Python
- ✓ Dashboard in Power BI & Tableau
- ✓ Business & Functional Requirement
- ✓ Social Media, Digital Marketing
- ✓ Biology, Medical Device Marketing
- ✓ CRM, Campaign Analyses

WORK EXPERIENCE

Premier Partner Experience Specialist | Meta, LA

Jun 2022-present

- Conduct end to end partner centric analyses on Digital Platform including requirement collection, design, configuration, data analyses, troubleshooting, dashboard creation and presentation
- Work closely with internal/external stakeholders in terms of workflow, solutions, issues, features and insight
- Created monthly Auditing Dashboard with summarized platform usage and issue statistics to improve support workflow on enhancement of partner experience, and helped customer achieving 30% target gain
- Daily REST API troubleshooting with partners, Dashboard delivery and presentation to clients

Senior Engagement Specialist | Seres Therapeutics

Jun 2021-Jun 2022

- Worked on a medicine program including donor data collection, donor identification, qualification, engagement and management in a predictive way using statistical analysis
- Created lead, planed campaign and identified donors in Salesforce to maintain the relationships; developed engagement opportunities by analyzing donors' behavior; produced Tableau dashboard for payment review
- Strategic planning on donor retention and recognition inactive donors through predictive churn analysis,
 which increase efficiency by 40%

EXPERIENCE – ACADEMIC INTERN

Graduate Consultant | Covenant Health Network

Feb 2021-May 2021

- Built dashboard using Power BI and pulled data from CMS to reflect real-time quality metrics
- Maintained data transformation in MS access database for queries, reporting and analysis needs.

Market Research Consultant | Hologic Inc.

Sep 2020-May 2021

• Conducted data collection on prioritizing improvement area of the U.S. medical devices market share through competitor analysis to monitor and maximize customer retention

Business Development Intern | Quick Biology Inc.

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Organized 3 years' data in customer database; identified methods of converting potential customers
- Created surveys to understand customer satisfaction, potential need and feedback for business improvement
 Business Analyst | California NanoSystems Institute
 Oct 2019 Dec 2019
- Researched on potential market capacity, opportunity for new medical product through competition analysis
- Planned FDA approval process to speed up the marketization and showcase unique feature of the product

EDUCATION

- Master of Business & Science | Keck Graduate Institute, Claremont, CA | Sep 2019 May 2021
- Bachelor of Economics | Michigan State University | Aug 2015 May 2019
- Certificate: Google Analytics 2022 | SQL for Data Analysis Udacity 2022

ACADEMIC PROJECT

- Case Analysis of Credit Risk Evaluation of a Bridge Loan
- Market Share Analysis on Big Buy Grocery Business
- Telecom Subscribers Addition Strategic Selections on business expanding
- Cosmetic Competitors Analysis by Category, Brand and Portfolio
- Monthly Income Statement Reporting Automation

Apr 2022

Mar 2022

Jan 2022 Nov 2022

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021